FEDERICO BENITEZ

FRONT END DEVELOPER

in O

CONTACT

EMAIL

fedebenitez1696@gmail.com

CURRENT LOCATIONCorrientes, Argentina

SKILLS

Soft Skills

Self-taught, teamwork and collaboration, proactive, empathetic, flexible and adaptable to different scenarios.

Hard Skills

BackEnd: NodeJs, ExpressJs,MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, RestAPI's, GraphQL.

FrontEnd: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, VanillaJS, ReactJS, SASS, VueJS, React Context, Redux, Typescript, React Native, Jest, NextJS.

Others: Git, Linux, BitBucket, GitLab.

PROFILE

I'm a Front-End Developer which is always trying to find optimal ways to code, on pursuit of improve on code quality and allow simplify problems.

I specialize on front-end develop with React and Redux.

Also I've experience on mobile develop with React-Native and backend development with NodeJS and ExpressJS with SQL and NoSQL DataBases like MongoDB, MySQL and SQL Server.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONT END DEVELOPER - MACRO INTELL S.A.

October 2021 - Current

- I'm part of a team which is creating a market place with React on frontend and NodeJS, Express and MongoDB on backend.
- Migrating Javascript code to Typescript, also fix of bugs and refactorize components with Redux Toolkit, React Query, Styled Components.
- Creating a cross-platform Mobile App with React Native.

MOBILE DEVELOPER- HOGAR MANTENIMIENTO

May 2021 - October 2021

- Responsible of the development of a mobile app with React
 Native and TypeScript for clients where it is possible to request
 the company's services.
- This application allows the company's technicians to complete routines, previously set up.
- The application allows technicians to see a list of pending and completed jobs. Being able to see information about it.
- Maintenance of an application developed with Quasar Framework. For the Back-End is used an API Rest developed with Symfony.

WEB DEVELOPER PHP - IPAP CHACO

March 2021 - April 2021

- In charge of development tasks, implementation of new features and maintenance of web development projects with PHP 5/7 and Symfony.
- Responsible for the creation of certificates for the participants of the trainings given by the organization.

EDUCATION

PROGRAMMING TECHNICIAN

NATIONAL TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY 2019 - 2022

LANGUAGES

- ENGLISH UPPER INTERMEDIATE
- SPANISH NATIVE